Bethlehem Business Women's Club; Records apap389
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Bethlehem Business Women's Club Records
1951-2019
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap389
2.45 cubic ft.
This collection documents the operations of the Bethlehem Business Women's Club from its inception in 1951.
Content Description
This collection includes scrapbooks, administrative records, newsletters, and newspaper clippings.
Historical Note
The Bethlehem Business Women's (BBW) Club was formed in December 1950 with 32 members and chartered in January 1951. The first president was Evelyn Sanvidge. It continues to be composed of women who live or work in the Town of Bethlehem, New York. The BBW offers an opportunity for its members to meet, network, and support the town through various community activities. Originally chartered as the Bethlehem Business and Professional Women's Club and a charter member of the New York Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs, the BBW broke away from the Federation in 1960 believing its money would be better spent within the Bethlehem community.
Today the BBW is comprised of local women of all ages with diverse backgrounds and interests. The Club provides college scholarships to graduating high school seniors who reside in the Town of Bethlehem and who have shown both academic achievement and community service during their high school years. Other community service activites include contributions to the local food pantry, participation in the Adopt-a-Highway program, and support of the local annual Holiday Community Dinner.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized alphabetically. There are no series.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Marilyn Kaltenborn donated all materials to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives in March 2021.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Bethlehem Business Women's Club; Businesswomen--New York (State); Women--New York (State)--Societies and Clubs; Women; Minutes (administrative records); Newsletters; Scrapbooks; Correspondence; Financial Records
- Bethlehem Business Women's Club, 50th Anniversary Scrapbook, #1, Created 2001, (1 of 2), 1951-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bethlehem Business Women's Club, 50th Anniversary Scrapbook, #1, Created 2001, (2 of 2), 1951-1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Bethlehem Business Women's Club, 50th Anniversary Scrapbook, #2, Created 2001, (1 of 2), 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bethlehem Business Women's Club, 50th Anniversary Scrapbook, #2, Created 2001, (2 of 2), 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bethlehem Business Women's Club, 50th Anniversary Scrapbook, #3, Created 2001, (1 of 2), 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bethlehem Business Women's Club, 50th Anniversary Scrapbook, #3, Created 2001, (2 of 2), 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bethlehem Business Women's Club, 50th Anniversary Scrapbook, #4, Created 2001, (1 of 2), 1975-1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bethlehem Business Women's Club, 50th Anniversary Scrapbook, #4, Created 2001, (2 of 2), 1975-1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bethlehem Business Women's Club, 50th Anniversary Scrapbook, #5, Created 2001, (1 of 2), 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bethlehem Business Women's Club, 50th Anniversary Scrapbook, #5, Created 2001, (2 of 2), 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Bethlehem Business Women's Club, 50th Anniversary Scrapbook, #6, Created 2001, (1 of 2), 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Bethlehem Business Women's Club, 50th Anniversary Scrapbook, #6, Created 2001, (2 of 2), 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Bethlehem Business Women's Club, 50th Anniversary Scrapbook, #7, Created 2001, 1990-1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Bethlehem Business Women's Club, 50th Anniversary Scrapbook, #8, Created 2001, (1 of 2), 1995-1999 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Bethlehem Business Women's Club, 50th Anniversary Scrapbook, #8, Created 2001, (2 of 2), 1995-1999 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Bethlehem Business Women's Club Scrapbook, 1953-1957 (Flat-file 1)
- Bethlehem Business Women's Club Scrapbook, 1989-1990; 1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Certificate of Incorporation, By-laws, Administrative Records, 1998; 2008; 2012; 2015 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Community Contacts Directory, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Financial Information, 1972-1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Fundraising, 2001-2003; Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Membership Applications and Brochures, 1968-2019; Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Membership Directories and Programs, 1967-1970 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Membership Directories and Programs, 1970-1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Membership Directories and Programs, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Membership Directories and Programs, 1991-2000 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Membership Directories and Programs, 2000-2010 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Membership Directories and Programs, 2010-2015 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Minutes, 1961-1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Newsletters, including Minutes and Reports, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Newsletters, including Minutes and Reports, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Newsletters, including Minutes and Reports, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Newsletters, including Minutes and Reports, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Newsletters, including Minutes and Reports, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Newsletters, including Minutes and Reports, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Newsletters, including Minutes and Reports, 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Newsletters, including Minutes and Reports, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Newsletters, including Minutes and Reports, 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Newsletters, including Minutes and Reports, 2008-2009 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Photograph Album, Party at Verstandig's, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Records, including Minutes, Newsletters, Reports, Correspondence, Event Materials (1 of 2), 1999-2004; Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Records, including Minutes, Newsletters, Reports, Correspondence, Event Materials (2 of 2), 1999-2004; Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Records, including Minutes, Newsletters, Reports, Correspondence, Event Materials (1 of 2), 2004-2008; Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Records, including Minutes, Newsletters, Reports, Correspondence, Event Materials (2 of 2), 2004-2008; Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Records, including Minutes, Newsletters, Reports, Correspondence, Event Materials, 2011-2015; Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Records, including Minutes, Newsletters, Reports, Correspondence, Event Materials (1 of 2), 2015-2019; Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Records, including Minutes, Newsletters, Reports, Correspondence, Event Materials (2 of 2), 2015-2019; Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Throw Project, 1999-2000; 2002-2003; Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Throw Project, 1999-2000; 2002-2003; Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)